# **BENOIT BOURGEON**

# .NET Software Developer

#### **PROFILE**

I am a full-stack developer specialized in .Net technologies.

I graduate 2 Masters in France specialized in IT related to the management of IT projects and artificial intelligence. I started my career in the industrial environment, insurance, and banking systems.

During the past 5 years, I have been working in England on web project various types of web projects: small to large scale. I know a variety of technologies and I am not scared to learn new frameworks.

I am looking for a new challenge and an opportunity to use my skills and discover new technologies on the web or not.

#### CONTACT

#### PHONE:

+44 7305 532428

#### WEBSITE:

https://benoitbourgeonportfolio.azurewebsites.net/

#### EMAIL:

benoit.bourgeon@yahoo.fr

### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

Full Stack Developer E-Commerce Website, PayPal API Designing SOA system Maintaining company websites

# **LANGUAGES**

French: native English: fluent Spanish: basic

## **HOBBIES**

Cinema Boxing Salsa Literature

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### BET365, Software Developer (UK)

August 2018-Actual

- Front End Developer (Agile, JIRA, GIT, Typescript, HTML/CSS, VB .NET, TSQL)
- Redesign of implementation Responsive website and improvement of the core system.

# **Granby Marketing, Software Developer (UK)**

May 2016-Jan 2018

- Maintenance in-house systems (Visual Studio 2015/2017, MVC4, VB .NET, C#, EF, LINQ, OpenID authentication, TFS, UI, Bootstrap, jQuery)
- Development promotional websites (Visual Studio 2017, ASP .NET MVC4/5, EF, LINQ, TFS, OpenID authentication, Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS)
- Specifications and test plans warehouse system (UML)
- Development warehouse system (Visual Studio 2017, SOA, .NET core, EF code first, Web API, RESTful, Angular, Bootstrap)

### QISoft, Support Developer (UK)

June 2015-February 2016

- Development of a process to optimize tests
- Customer support and reporting bugs (Agile)

## Société Général, Maintenance Developer (FR)

Maintenance of improvement of the back-office system (Linux, C, Oracle)
October 2014–June 2015

# Wyde MPhasis, Software Developer (FR)

Development and configuration of insurance system

April 2014-October 2014

#### Multitoll, Software Developer (FR)

- Conception and development of a new toll system (C++, Qt4, Uml, Php, Java)
- Improvement of the system for banking transaction (PERL)

September 2009-September 2013

# **SKILLS**

Web Technologies & Frameworks: ASP .NET MVC, Typescript, Angular, AngularJS,

HTML/CSS (SASS), knockout

Programming language and database: C#, C++/C, Qt4/5, JAVA, Perl, SQL Server

Scripts/UI: jQuery, Bootstrap

Versioning and other tools: GIT, TFS, Jira, Jenkins

# **EDUCATION**

## **University of Cergy Pontoise**

2012 - 2013

Masters 2 SIC (Intelligence and Communication Systems)

### **ITESCIA**

2009 - 2012

Masters 2 M2I (Master of Information Technology Engineering)